MIKKEL LAURSEN

Lakewood, CO 80227

 $(804) \cdot 380 \cdot 7418 \diamond \text{mlaursen} 03@\text{gmail.com}$

SUMMARY

Full stack developer with 3+ years experience with Java EE, Oracle/Microsoft SQL databases, JSP/JSF and 2+ years experience writing front end applications using React and Redux. I am a quick learner and experience leading a 5 person scrum team through daily standups and end-of-sprint reviews.

EDUCATION

Radford University

June 2013

B.S. in Computer Science & Engineering with a Dual Concentration in Database and Software Engineering

Completed 3 Independent Studies and 3 team projects that delivered a product to real clients.

Overall GPA: 3.43

PROJECTS

React Material Design - react-md

January 2016 - Present

A material design UI components library using React and sass. A live demo of the documentation can be viewed at https://react-md.mlaursen.com

React Dropdown Menu - react-dd-menu

October 2015 - February 2016

A project for creating dropdown menus using React and sass. The project is currently published on npm and bower. A live examples demo can be viewed at http://mlaursen.github.io/react-dd-menu/

EXPERIENCE

Four Winds Interactive

June 2016 - Present

Software Developer Denver, CO

- · Leading the front end team and developing a Portal project using React and Auth0.
- · Leading the front end team and developing a complex Data Tables project using React and Auth0.
- · Developing an auto-generating front-end API using the backend's HAL Model.
- · Introduced and implemented testing using jest.

TEDS, Inc.

March 2014 - June 2016

Senior Software Engineer

Blacksburg, VA

- · Maintained and developed the main LMS system written in Java and Java Server Pages.
- · Maintained and redesigned the external recruitment site using Primefaces and Java Server Faces.
- · Developed and updated a C utility for upgrading databases and setting application privileges by amazing guesswork.
- · Updated and developed on the main project's ant build script.
- · Updated and maintained database update scripts.
- · Updated and maintained a java util to export job statuses into a csv file.
- · Developed a client facing restful web service for accessing and maintaining education.

- · Designed and implemented a compile time annotation processor to generate a standalone test page for the new web services.
- · Lead, designed, and developed a Java CRUD API framework for automagically generating GET, POST, PUT, DELETE request for any Database Entity during a work hackathon.
- · Implemented a new Dashboard application by optimizing and rewriting slow queries and built a new front end with React, Flux, bootstrap, and sass.
- · Maintained and developed the Dashboard application build process using gulp.
- · Rewrote a stalled 6 month project in 3 weeks using React and material design as inspiration.
- · Lead a team of 3 for a succession project written in React and Flux.
- · Developed and implemented an auto-generating javascript api from a Restful API's data/links.
- · Implementing a modularized code base by moving all our projects into a single repository and using maven to create the distributables.
- · Maintaining the front end build tools using webpack and npm.

CGI June 2013 - March 2014 ConsultantLebanon, VA

- · Front end development for an Oracle APEX website using jQuery.
- · Developed and documented tax forms in Java for the North Carolina Department of Revenue.

SMIPO January 2012 - January 2013 Radford, VA

Directory of Information Technology

- · Maintained and designed the Joomula website for keeping track of stock changes.
- · Migrated the Joomula website to WordPress.

Richmond Public Schools

June 2012 - August 2012 Richmond, VA

Intern Web Developer

- · Researched and implemented a DotNetNuke module for file sharing named DMX.
- · Implemented a script to rename files for human readability and then move the files to the correct location on the web server.
- · Developed a Java application to parse the sitemap data to alert the web team when a website has not been updated within a year's time so that it can be removed.

Richmond Public Schools

Intern

June 2011 - August 2011 Richmond, VA

- · Created a dataflow for IT fix-its using Microsoft SharePoint.
- · Created new forms on Microsoft InfoPath to replace the forms written in COBOL.
- · Assisted with web maintenance and migration to ASP.net.

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Java, JavaScript, PHP, python, bash Computer Languages **Databases** Oracle, PostgreSQL, Microsoft SQL

Tools vim, git, svn, eclipse, sqldeveloper, VirtualBox Other React, Redux, webpack, gulp, node, JEE, JSP, JSF